<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>swift 4.1 on Fresh Swift</title>
    <link>https://freshswift.net/tags/swift-4.1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in swift 4.1 on Fresh Swift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freshswift.net/tags/swift-4.1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reduce boilerplate code with an automatic synthesis of Equatable and Hashable conformance</title>
      <link>https://sarunw.com/posts/reduce-boilerplate-code-with-automatic-synthesis-of-equatable-and-hashable-conformance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>In this post, Sarun Wongpatcharapakorn takes us back to Swift 4.1 to look at the automatic synthesis of the Equatable and Hashable protocols. Even if you are already familiar with this feature, it&#39;s helpful to be reminded of how it can be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whats new in Swift 4.1?</title>
      <link>https://github.com/twostraws/whats-new-in-swift-4-1</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 09:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>To demonstrate what’s new in Swift 4.1, Paul Hudson has created this Xcode playground. The playground includes code samples for all the new Swift 4.1 features we have been looking forward to. Very handy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditional conformances in Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.swiftbysundell.com/posts/conditional-conformances-in-swift</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 10:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>John Sundell looks at Conditional Conformance, a new Swift feature included in the recent Swift 4.1 release. Conditional conformance is a great addition to the language, and John demonstrates how we can use it to write code in a recursive fashion, while reducing duplication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating to Swift 4.1</title>
      <link>https://www.avanderlee.com/swift/update-to-swift-4-1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 15:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>With the recent release of Swift 4.1, Antoine van der Lee gives us a quick rundown of what we need to do to update our Swift code to the latest version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift 4.1 Released!</title>
      <link>https://swift.org/blog/swift-4-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 10:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>Ted Kremenek with a post announcing the official release of Swift 4.1 🚀. Although this is only a minor language release, there are some really nice updates included. Onwards and upwards!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift 4.1 Release Process</title>
      <link>https://swift.org/blog/swift-4-1-release-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 03:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>It’s so great to see the plans for Swift 4.1 being published already, considering the recent release of Swift 4. Here, on the official Swift blog, Ted Kremenek describes the goals, release process, and estimated schedule for Swift 4.1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
