<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tuples on Fresh Swift</title>
    <link>https://freshswift.net/tags/tuples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tuples on Fresh Swift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freshswift.net/tags/tuples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using tuples to Complex Sorting Operations in Swift</title>
      <link>https://holyswift.app/using-tuples-to-complex-sorting-operations-in-swift</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>The Swift standard library contains several overloads of the &lt; comparison operator used to compare tuples of various sizes. In this post, Leonardo Maia Pugliese demonstrates how to use these overloads to implement complex sorting operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift Unwrapped #86: Tuples</title>
      <link>https://spec.fm/podcasts/swift-unwrapped/fxMk4ipF</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>Tuples are a Swift compound type consisting of a comma-separated list of types, enclosed in parentheses. They are probably most often used to return multiple values from a function. In this episode of the Swift Unwrapped podcast, Jesse Squires and JP Simard use a Swift evolution proposal as a starting point for a discussion about tuples, and compare the type against named types such as structures and classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Swift 4 change is objectively bad</title>
      <link>https://twitter.com/jckarter/status/867766410172182528</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 09:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>Interesting Twitter thread regarding what looks like an undesirable change coming in Swift 4. The change relates to how tuples are automatically expanded in closures and it&#39;s something to be mindful of as we approach the Swift 4 release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Label-Directed Tuple Assignments</title>
      <link>http://ericasadun.com/2017/05/08/evolving-label-directed-tuple-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 07:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>Really interesting post from Erica Sadun on an undocumented feature of Swift - the use of tuple labels to mix and match tuple declarations with values. This is sometimes called a &#34;tuple shuffle&#34;. Obscure and slightly complex.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
