<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>array on Fresh Swift</title>
    <link>https://freshswift.net/tags/array/</link>
    <description>Recent content in array on Fresh Swift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freshswift.net/tags/array/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grouping Array Elements With Dictionary in Swift</title>
      <link>https://swiftsenpai.com/swift/group-array-elements-with-dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>Swift 5 introduced a new initializer for Dictionary, which allows us to create a dictionary of grouped elements from an input array. Here, Lee Kah Seng demonstrates how we can use this initializer to group array elements based on a custom property of the array element type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift tip: Building arrays with compactMap</title>
      <link>https://www.jessesquires.com/blog/swift-tip-building-arrays-with-compactmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 08:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>Jesse Squires demonstrates how we can use the Swift compactMap function to build arrays of optional items, while maintaining the intended order of the items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hack for fixed-size arrays in Swift</title>
      <link>https://oleb.net/blog/2017/12/fixed-size-arrays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 15:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>This is an interesting post from Ole Begemann. He discusses something he found in the Swift standard library - a template implementation for a fixed-size array. This is a type not found in the standard library, and Ole shows us why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weak Arrays</title>
      <link>https://www.objc.io/blog/2017/12/28/weak-arrays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 17:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>This short post from Objc.io shows us how to create a Collection type which references it’s elements weakly. As standard Swift collections reference their elements strongly, this might come in useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArraySlice In Swift</title>
      <link>https://marcosantadev.com/arrayslice-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 10:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <description>Marco Santarossa with a post about the Swift ArraySlice type. He shows us how to create them, describes the relationship between ArraySlice and Array, and demonstrates how ArraySlice indices work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
